[insect buzzing]
[waves crashing]
[creature calling]
[snarling]
[screeching]
[snarling continues]
[bird screeches]
[birds screeching]
[sniffing]
[roaring]
[snarling]
[roars]
[roaring]
[dramatic music playing]
[chittering]
[roaring]
[shrieking]
[chittering]
[prey shrieks]
["Under Pressure" by Queen
and David Bowie playing]
[grunting]
♪ Pressure pushing down on me ♪
[breathing heavily]
♪ Pressing down on you
No man ask for ♪
♪ Under pressure
That burns a building down ♪
♪ Splits a family in two ♪
♪ Puts people on streets ♪
♪ It's the terror of knowing ♪
♪ What this world is about ♪
♪ Watching some good friends ♪
♪ Screaming, "Let me out"♪
♪ Pray tomorrow
Gets me higher ♪
♪ Pressure on people
People on streets ♪
- [indistinct chatter]
- [captain] It's highly toxic.
Come on, lads, keep it moving.
Keep it moving.
[crewman 1] Go, go, go!
[men talking indistinctly]
Is this double pay or what?
There is toxic waste.
[captain] What are you doing
sitting there, mate?
- You're almost there.
- [camera shutter clicks]
I want this filth off my ship
as fast as possible.
[parrot squawks]
[squawking]
[camera shutter clicking]
[parrot] What you doing, then?
[squawks]
Naughty. [squawking]
Help! Help!
Naughty.
Shh.
- [squawks]
- Keep your little beak shut.
[parrot] Not very nice.
Otherwise,
you'll go for a swim.
- [man speaking indistinctly]
- Help! Help!
Help me! Help me!
- Hey.
- Ah. Well done.
I'm here from the home office.
[parrot] Bullshit.
Here checking on,
uh, security protocols...
[camera whirring]
...and, um, taking
a few pictures, so smile.
- [camera shutter clicks]
- [both grunting]
What are you doing in here?
[groans]
- [parrot] Not very nice.
- What's going on?
[grunting]
That's him!
- I'll get you!
- [crewman shouts indistinctly]
[crewman grunts]
[grunts]
[panting]
[screams, grunts]
[crewman 2] Hey, hey!
Get at this!
[speaks indistinctly]
[chain rattles]
[all grunting]
- [crewman 3] Get up.
- [crewman 4] Get Him down!
- [screams]
- [grunts]
You two, go left!
Cut him off!
I want him caught,
dead or dead.
[grunting]
[captain] Not there!
Go around! Go around!
There you go, mate.
End of the line.
[Jonas] Okay.
You're all under arrest.
- [crewman 4] Huh?
- For the illegal dumping
- of radioactive materials.
- [man scoffs]
Yeah, you, you,
you, you and you.
What, me and...
and him, and him? And him?
- Kill him.
- [Jonas] Wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait.
I know.
You want to see the warrant.
It's right in my pocket.
[exhales]
I'll see you in court, yeah?
We're out of shipping lanes,
and you're 200 miles
from shore.
So enjoy your swim.
[engines roaring]
I've got him.
Just off the port side.
He's like a green James Bond.
I like it.
[captain] Oh, no, my hat!
[Mac] Hello, suckers.
Looks like
he's been making friends.
Wherever he goes,
people just love him.
God knows why.
[engines roaring]
Do you got this?
We'll see.
Maybe this wasn't
the best idea.
Maybe this isn't
[sighs] This is gonna be awesome.
[Mac] Define "awesome."
[Rigas] I'm about to.
- [inhales]
- Opening hatch.
[plane rumbling]
Next time, put a little
more air in this thing.
It's like breathing
through a straw.
Worked, didn't it?
You okay?
If you love your job,
you'll never work a day
in your life.
[both chuckle]
[Curtis] Okay,
bring in Test 15.
Initiating suit power-up.
[man] Clear.
[machine whirs]
["Dare" by Gorillaz playing]
Promising.
[Curtis] The exo suit
is performing way beyond
what we expected, Jiuming.
[grunting]
[Curtis] 21% increase in power.
Not bad, huh?
So cool.
I can't wait to use these
in the trench.
Hi.
[in Mandarin]
What's up favourite niece?
I'm supposed
to tell you not to be
late for the party tonight.
Of course.
- [in English] Maybe 25. Hmm?
- Okay.
[Meiying] I mean it,
don't be late!
[indistinct chatter]
[Mac] I cannot believe
you got this far in life
without knowing
how to tie a tie.
First, let's not overstate
how far I've gotten in life.
Second, never involved wearing
a monkey suit.
- Perfect. You look great.
- Thanks.
Ah. Maybe this is the start
of something.
[sighs] Don't count on it.
[both chuckle]
Hi.
[Jonas] That guy look familiar
to you?
No.
- [Jonas] I don't like him.
- You don't like anyone.
[sighs] I like you.
That's 'cause I save
your life all the time...
I buy you beers
and I back you up
in bar fights.
It's 'cause
you're a special guy.
You're both special.
[inhales sharply]
- Wish me luck.
- [both] Good luck.
Thanks for the money.
[woman] Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to
the 10th anniversary
of the Oceanic Institute.
I'm Hilary Driscoll.
Thank you for coming tonight,
and for joining me
in funding
this incredible work.
[guests clapping]
Stop. Don't fidget.
Why exactly do I have to be
up here anyway?
[breathes deeply]
'Cause you're a team player.
Great.
Please give a warm welcome
to the director
of the Institute...
[guests cheering]
...Zhang Jiuming.
Thank you, Hilary.
[in Mandarin] As the great
poet Song Lian said...
"Man is limited
only by his imagination."
My father named me Jiuming,
which means ocean
or abyss.
My father and my sister
spent their lives
studying the ocean.
It wasn't until
they were both gone
that I began to wonder
what my purpose was.
But through Suyin's daughter Meiying,
I saw that there was a future.
I merged
my father's research institute
with my company
to carry forward
the spirit of exploring
the unknown in their honor.
[guests cheering]
[in Mandarin] To mark
this tenth anniversary,
I want to introduce you all
to someone very special.
[device clicks]
[water sloshing]
[in Mandarin]
Her name is Haiqi.
She is the world's
only megalodon in captivity.
We found her injured as a pup.
Thanks to Haiqi, we've learned
a tremendous amount
about the megalodons
as well as the trench
where they live.
[in English] Thanks
to the generous donations
from our supporters,
we have been able
to create the technology
to pass through
the thermocline,
a thermal layer
of freezing cold water
that separates Haiqi's world
from ours
and into a trench 6,000 meters
below sea level.
Thanks to you,
we have the ability
to go further
than ever before.
[in Mandarin] Love the ocean
and protect the ocean.
Thank you
[guests cheering]
[Driscoll, in English]
And thank you. Zhang Jiuming.
So, thank you all
for being part of protecting
this incredible ecosystem.
[applause]
Thank you for coming.
[greets in Mandarin]
[in Mandarin] Do you think
there are more creatures
to be discovered down there?
There has to be.
[Mac, in English]
Who wants to get a selfie
with the man
who fought a megalodon
and lived to tell the tale?
We give you,
ladies and gentlemen,
Jonas Taylor.
- [guests cheering]
- There he is! There he is.
I know this was your idea.
- [camera shutter clicking]
- I'm gonna kill you.
Smile and pretend you love it.
[Mac] Go on, give him a hug.
Give him a tickle.
Oh, he loves people.
[waves splashing]
[ominous music playing]
[Meiying] I wanna go
to Mana One with you.
I want to dive the trench.
No.
Sorry, Meiying.
Why not?
Mom was diving all the time
at my age.
Not to 25,000 feet.
Saying it's too dangerous?
Too dangerous for you.
But not dangerous.
In psychology, they call
that "cognitive dissonance."
In the real world,
they call it "parenting."
You need to start
taking me seriously
as a scientist.
- You're 14.
- Exactly.
I know every system
on Mana One,
every dive protocol
and every animal
we've seen down there.
[sighs] Hey, look.
You can come to Mana One.
To observe the dive.
And that's it. [exhales]
Jiuming is swimming
with the meg.
Uncle.
[indistinct announcement]
[Curtis] Haiqi's vitals
are elevated.
Be careful,
she's definitely aware of you.
[Jonas, over radio]
Why are you swimming
with the meg, Jiuming?
I'm conducting an experiment.
Is the experiment
"Do I taste good?"
[in Mandarin]
Uncle, are you crazy?
[in English] It's okay.
I've been training Haiqi
since she was a pup.
A meg is not trainable, Jiuming.
But if you wanna be eaten
in front of your niece,
go ahead.
Fifty bucks says
this is gonna end badly.
I'll take that action.
[Sal] I am all in
for team shark.
[DJ] What? You can't bet
on a shark, man.
That's bad karma.
Come on, guys, focus.
That's not cool.
Jiuming...
I'd like
to respectfully suggest
that this is truly
a terrible idea.
Megs and humanity
were never meant to mix.
[radio beeps]
Haiqi and I
have a special bond.
Watch this.
One click to come.
Two clicks to go.
- [device clicks]
- [breathing heavily]
[device clicks]
[Lance] Whoa.
I think she's looking at us.
You see?
[Curtis] She's coming around.
Heart rate is up.
- Moving in fast.
- [beeping]
[Lance, over radio]
Four hundred meters.
[in Mandarin] Slowly, slowly.
[computer beeping rapidly]
[Curtis, in English] Jiuming,
she's not responding.
[Jiuming] Come on, Haiqi.
[Lance] Two hundred meters.
- One hundred meters.
- [device clicks]
[Curtis] Jiuming, move.
It's too late.
She's coming in too fast.
[Lance] Fifty meters.
[Mac] Pull the cord.
[Lance] Twenty meters.
[Mac] Jiuming,
get out of there!
- [Meiying] Uncle, no!
- [slams]
[metal groans]
Did it get him?
I don't know.
I couldn't watch.
I don't see him.
I knew this was a bad idea.
[door opens]
[in Mandarin] Total success.
[DJ laughing]
[Meiying] [in Mandarin]
Uncle! Are you crazy?
[Jiuming] It's all right,
I'm good.
Huh? [chuckles]
[in English]
That was exciting, huh?
I can't figure out
what's wrong with her.
She's been acting strangely
all week.
[Jonas] You can clickety-click
all you want.
The problem is
that it's a meg.
And you're a snack.
- [woman] Yeah.
- [indistinct chatter]
For the record, you scared
the hell out of Meiying.
You're one to talk.
What were you doing
on that ship?
Actually, don't tell me.
I don't wanna know.
Well, the Institute's mandate
is to protect the oceans, right?
We can't be a part
of any illegal activity.
Oh, I abhor lawlessness.
Oh, good.
Especially the illegal dumping
of radioactive waste.
You're taking
bigger and bigger risks
each time you go out.
Well, I guess
we both know about that.
It's not the same.
With me,
there's a calculation
of risks.
Not that I see.
Do you miss your mom,
big fish?
- [man] Doctor Howard.
- [indistinct chatter]
Are you ready for Mana One?
[in Mandarin]
Yes, whenever you're ready?
These new suits will let us
travel anywhere and at
any depth underwater.
[Meiying, in English] Say.
- [beeps]
- [machine whirrs]
- What?
- [yelping]
[in Mandarin]
No worries, no worries.
[Meiying] Mom and Grandpa
talked about you all the time.
Nothing good I suppose.
Wanna guess?
See this scar?
When I was 11
my father was busy in the lab.
So I snuck out to swim with my
friends on the rocky shores...
and had to get nine stitches
as a result of it.
When I returned home my father
taught me a real lesson.
- Grandpa?
- Of course.
He was kind to you
because you're
his granddaughter,
but he was tough on me.
So after college,
I started a company.
I wanted to get away from him.
I hadn't had any contact
with your grandfather
for many years.
Then he asked your mum
to bring me this calligraphy.
"Dragon travelling
across the Four Seas."
I thought it was
a form of ridicule...
but I came to realize that
he wanted me to
find my own way.
[helicopter whirring]
[Jiuming] [in Mandarin]
Like the dragon...
I hope you can find
your own fate.
[in English] Ground crew,
we're approaching Mana One.
[crew member, over radio] Hey,
Rigas. Good to have you back.
[Rigas] I missed you guys.
[crew member] Are you ready
to do some diving?
[Rigas] You know it.
[waves splashing]
[suspenseful music playing]
[metal creaking]
- [wind whooshing]
- [water splashing]
[Mac, over radio]
Morning, everyone.
Let's get this show underwater.
[Jess, over radio]
Dive 1 and Dive 2,
descend to 25,000 feet.
We're exploring Area 19.
Collecting rock samples
and logging any new species.
[DJ, over radio]
Diving in T-minus 20 minutes.
All eyes open
for a straightforward
sweep and scan. The usual.
Yeah.
There's no usual down there.
- System's up.
- [system powering up]
What's with
all these toys you have
hanging around your console,
Lance?
[gas hisses]
They're not toys,
they're figurines.
[Mac] They are
definitely toys, Lance.
- [chuckles]
- Thank you.
[crank whirring]
[Jess] Ready for the drop,
guys?
[rumbling]
[enthralling music playing]
So, are you and Sal, like,
Comic-Con guys or what?
Uh, absolutely right. Yeah.
Do you, um, dress up?
Uh, yeah.
Don't get him started,
unless you want to see
a million photographs.
[Rigas, chuckling]
Oh, yes, please.
[Jonas, over radio]
Stay focused, guys.
[DJ] Passing 17,000.
[Jess] Telemetry's good.
It's a beautiful day
in the neighborhood.
[captivating music playing]
Passing 18,000 feet.
All systems nominal.
Looking good, team.
Let's pull up the grids
we're gonna map today.
[Lance, over radio] Area 19.
When are we going to
look at something different?
[Curtis] You know,
there's like 100 more
sectors to explore.
Jonas,
can you confirm O2 levels?
[Jonas] Consumption is 11%
over mission spec.
Guess Rigas is nervous.
More like
you're a mouth breather.
- [chuckles]
- He totally is.
[Rigas] Can feel the breeze
from over here.
[Jonas] Yeah.
Firstly, it's called
a deviated septum.
Second, I distinctly remember
deviating it
while saving
your ungrateful ass
from a 70-foot megalodon.
Passing 20,000 feet.
Approaching the thermocline.
Checking O2 lines
and tank pressure.
[Sal] Well,
if there was a leak,
there would be
a fluctuation on the readings.
I'm not seeing anything here.
[Curtis] Check the pressure
on the auxiliary O2 tanks.
[Sal] Okay, I'll check again.
That's not the problem.
Uh, Jonas?
Meiying?
[in Mandarin]
What the hell are you doing?
[in English]
You gotta be kidding me.
I see that you're angry.
But I believe
that this is a reasonable
and responsible decision.
Stop the dive.
[submarine slows down]
Full stop.
But before you start yelling,
can I just say... [sighs]
I did all kinds
of stupid things
when I was 14.
And look how I turned out.
We're surfacing.
[Meiying] But I don't see
what the problem is.
This is your 26th trench dive
without incident.
Subs have electric
predator countermeasures,
and emergency dive suits.
Which you don't have.
Actually...
I packed one while you were
doing the pre-dive meeting.
You know,
now's maybe
a good time to, uh,
sit down
and be quiet for a minute.
I can do a seatbelt by myself,
you know.
[Jonas] I know you can.
[Jiuming, over radio] Jonas.
It's not your call, Jiuming.
We've got company.
[scanner trilling]
Guys, it's a meg.
- [alarm blaring]
- [Sal] Approaching fast.
That's not possible.
they can't go through
the thermocline.
It's not come
from the thermocline.
I'm tracking it
from the shore.
Dive! Flank speed!
[Sal] Engaging.
Rerouting battery array.
[Rigas] Hold on.
Charging
the predator countermeasures.
We'll be dead
before they're online.
Thermocline's our only hope.
I'm reading Haiqi's tracker.
[sighs] Impossible.
[DJ over radio] Well,
impossible just got possible.
Five hundred meters
to the thermocline.
[Lance, over radio]
Haiqi's closing fast.
[Sal] One hundred meters.
She's right above us.
Come on, come on!
[Rigas, over radio]
Entering the thermocline.
Dive 1, Dive 2.
Switch to low-frequency light.
you don't want to attract
any more megs.
[Jiuming, over radio]
I've lost her.
She can't follow us through.
[Lance, over radio] Can she?
[Rigas, over radio]
Going dark.
I've never crossed
the thermocline at 60 knots.
[Jess] Careful. You don't want
to burn out the engines.
Don't worry, I'm not gonna
break the pretty toys.
[rumbling]
Yes.
She's still on us.
[Jiuming, over radio]
Thirty seconds
- for the countermeasures.
- Evasive.
She must have followed
our heat signature.
[Meiying yelps]
[submarine rumbling]
[Rigas, over radio]
How did your pet shark
get down here, Jiuming?
[Jiuming]
She must have escaped.
How did that happen?
[Sal] Predator countermeasures active.
[electricity crackles]
Proximity alert.
Megs.
No way.
[foreboding music playing]
[Rigas] That's the biggest meg
I've ever seen.
Biggest meg
anyone's ever seen.
That's gotta be
the apex predator.
[submarine thuds]
[Jiuming, over radio]
Incredible. Megs are solitary.
It's like
they're being called.
I'm changing the dive plan.
We have to see
what they're up to.
And what about Meiying?
Well, I vote we go.
I wasn't asking you.
[Jiuming, over radio] Oxygen
reserves are at maximum.
Predator countermeasures
are deployed.
Right now
we are perfectly safe.
Right now, yeah.
If I see anything dangerous,
I'm pulling the plug.
[Jiuming, over radio]
Mac, we're changing
the mission profile.
Proceeding on heading 227.
Now, they're already
off mission.
They need to stay on course.
Jonas,
you're going way outside
the sector we have
already mapped.
[Jiuming, over radio] This is
an exploration mission.
Let's explore.
Copy that.
- [sighs]
- Eyes open, watch your backs.
Really, Mac?
So, we're gonna follow
some giant sharks
to a unknown sector?
[clicks tongue] Man...
This some dumbass shit,
mark my words.
[automated voice]
Entering sector 21.
[mysterious music playing]
Commencing geographical scan.
It's so beautiful.
Your mum loved this place
more than anything.
I'm glad
I finally get to see it.
Don't get used to it.
You're grounded
for the rest of your life.
[Meiying] I love you, too.
[Jonas chuckles]
[Lance, over radio] Haiqi
400 meters ahead and holding.
[Meiying, over radio]
Where are we going now?
[Rigas, over radio]
Into the unknown.
[Jiuming, over radio]
That's what we came for.
I've got
Haiqi's tracker ahead.
Looks like she's circling.
[sonar beeping]
Look up.
It's some
instinctual gathering.
[Rigas] Incredible.
They're here to mate.
This is why Haiqi has been
acting strangely.
Oh, great.
More megs.
- [scanner beeping rapidly]
- [alarm blaring]
The scanner's detecting
an abnormal structure.
No way.
[Curtis] Is that a wreck?
It's some kind of
sea floor station.
What could they be
doing down here?
Rigas, run all spectrums.
[Rigas] No, that's no wreck.
I'm getting
heat signatures off it.
[Rigas, over radio]
Just can't see what's inside.
[Jiuming, over radio]
Multiple airlocks,
power generation.
The resources needed
is staggering.
Who would even have
that technology?
[sonar beeping]
Sonar says
there's something above us.
It looks like a submarine.
Let's take a look.
[automated voice] Charges set.
Priming zone for detonation.
[man] Come on.
We need to blow this ridge.
[diver, over radio]
Yeah, okay, okay.
We don't wanna be down here
any longer than needs be.
[man, over radio] Yeah, well,
this is the only place
to mine this stuff.
Slow and steady.
[diver] Hey, Montes.
Why do you get to stay
in the submarine?
[Montes] It's good
to be the king.
[automated voice]
Incoming object detected.
[sonar beeping]
[Montes] Zoom in 400%.
[speaking Spanish]
[Montes, in English]
Mana One crew is below us.
There's no way
they haven't seen the station.
[diver] What are we gonna do?
[Montes] I'm arming
the explosives right now.
You have to get out.
What? Wait, no,
you can't do that.
There isn't time.
You know there isn't time.
It will take ten minutes
to get clear.
Montes!
Sorry, guys.
[diver] Montes!
Montes, don't do it!
[Sal, over radio]
What was that?
Landslide!
I can't get ahead of it.
I'm gonna have to go through.
[alarm blaring]
- [Montes grunting]
- [alarm blaring]
[Montes grunts]
[Jess] Guys?
What's happening?
I'm reading
a thermocline breach.
Something's ripped
a giant hole in it.
Rerouting the thrusters.
This is all we've got.
[yelps]
Vertical control is down.
Hydraulics are non-responsive.
We're pinned.
[Jiuming] Coming in.
- [Jiuming] Hold us steady.
- [inhales sharply] Yeah.
[Jonas, over radio] Jiuming.
Sixty degrees down.
Two feet forward.
Jiuming!
[alarm blaring]
Go, go, go!
Full thrust! Full thrust!
- [Jiuming gasps]
- [grunts]
[Jonas] Jiuming!
[Meiying] No!
[DJ] There's no telemetry.
Dive 1, Dive 2. Do you copy?
[DJ] We've got nothing here.
Keep trying, DJ. Jess,
prep the rescue sub. Stat.
- Ugh, what happened?
- I don't know.
How do we know
if they're still alive?
Prep the rescue vehicle.
[DJ] Dive 1, Dive 2.
Do you copy?
Come on, Jonas.
[Jonas, echoing] Meiying.
[Meiying coughing]
[echoing] Meiying.
- Meiying.
- [electricity crackles]
[Meiying] What happened?
[Jonas] Took a nasty hit.
Uncle Jiuming?
Where's Uncle Jiuming?
- Where is he?
- We can't raise him.
Hey. We work the problems
one by one.
We do what's in front of us...
[crying]
...and then we do
the next thing.
We're gonna be okay.
[Jess] Mac!
The rescue sub isn't working.
[over radio] The battery array
was deliberately shorted out.
It looks like sabotage.
How's that possible?
This isn't a secure area.
There are 30 people
who work here.
Well, how long to fix it?
It's the control boards, Mac.
There is no fixing it.
[Rigas] Try it now.
[Meiying] What's our status?
[Jonas] No comms, no heat.
We're losing air fast.
[Rigas] This isn't working.
Flood in my extra O2.
Already done.
[Sal] I've got one last idea.
Route the power
through the heating cell.
[radio static]
I got Dive 1.
Mac, I got Dive 1.
- Jonas?
- [Jonas chuckles over radio]
Good to hear your voice, Mac.
Not as good as it is
to hear yours, brother.
Talk to me.
[smacks lips] It ain't good.
Almost every system is down,
and we're losing air fast.
We'll get into
the emergency dive suits...
and we're gonna need
a ride up.
Jonas...
it's not gonna be possible.
What are you talking about?
The battery array.
It shorted out
the control board
in the rescue sub.
We're investigating it now.
Jonas?
Jonas, can you hear me?
Jonas, we can't get to you.
[breathing heavily]
We're gonna walk.
We're gonna walk back
across the trench.
Make it into
that sea floor station.
And we're gonna get inside.
And then we're gonna get
to the surface.
Those suits have
two hours of air tops.
They're only designed
for brief extravehicular work.
We'll go slow and steady.
They'll hold.
It's three kilometers.
You'll be defenseless
out there.
What do you want from me, Mac?
This is what we got, and this
is what we're gonna do.
[breathing heavily]
Half our team is dead,
and I'm not losing
the other half.
[automated voice]
Beginning suit initialization.
Joint actuators functioning.
Ultrasonic signal
communications online.
Initialization complete.
Abandoning Dive 1, Mac.
[air hisses]
The radios won't relay
to the surface,
so we're going dark.
Talk to you on the other side.
Godspeed, Jonas.
[automated voice]
Emergency escape initiated.
[distant chittering]
[Jiuming, over radio]
Hey. Whoa!
Almost killed you.
The hell are you doing?
Saving your ass.
And walking back
to that station.
What are you doing?
Saving your ass.
And walking back
to that station.
- Don't have much time.
- Let's get going.
- Jiu.
- Oh.
[in Mandarin]
Uncle, I thought you--
You're not going
to get rid of me that easily.
[Rigas, in English] Hey.
Hey. Let me check.
[automated voice] Air left...
Hey, you need to calm down
or you're gonna
run out of oxygen, Lance.
[breathes heavily]
I don't think i can.
[Rigas] Think of it as cosplay.
[Sal, chuckling] Or we could
be paintballing.
[Curtis] Like the ultimate
team-building exercise.
[Jonas] We need
to cover distance
while the megs
are still occupied.
[automated voice] Three
kilometers to destination.
[Meiying] Away from the megs
is fine by me.
[Jiuming] We're a strong group.
We can do this.
Amazing.
Lighting courtesy
of Mother Nature.
[Sal] It's incredible,
there are new species
all around us.
Hey. Look.
Look at this.
It's beautiful.
[Lance] Hello,
my little biolum--
[screaming]
There's a snake!
Get this monster off my head!
[screaming]
[grunts, breathes heavily]
No touching stuff.
[Lance, breathing heavily]
He started it.
[Mac] Everyone
clear the station.
DJ, what's our time on Jonas?
[DJ] Forty-one minutes
since they went dark.
At best,
it'll take another hour
for them
to cover the distance.
Listen up.
We know there's some kind of
rogue operation in the trench.
Now, some bastard's
got his fingers
in our operation here.
That sub was
definitely sabotaged,
so we've got a mole
on the station.
DJ, I want you to pull
all surveillance footage
from the sub bay
for the last 24 hours.
Jess, run the personnel files
on the crew,
look for anything suspect.
We're gonna get
these sons of bitches,
but we have to watch
our own backs.
One of us mans the DCC
at all times, understood?
Yes.
[Rigas, breathing heavily]
Is it just me,
or does walking
three kilometers underwater
sound like hard work?
[Curtis] It certainly wasn't
on my to-do list.
[Lance] Baby octopi.
So many colors.
That's incredible.
[breathing heavily]
[Meiying] Anybody wanna play
a game?
[Jiuming] A game?
[Rigas] This isn't a game.
She means to keep
our minds occupied.
[Rigas] Right now, my mind is
pretty damn occupied.
[breathes heavily, yelps]
[panting]
[Lance screaming]
There's a... there's a...
It's... [screams]
Lance?
What was it?
- [Curtis] I didn't see.
- [Sal] Where's Lance?
[Sal] Is it a meg?
[Sal] Some... something's
happened to him. I know it.
[Jiuming] Lance?
[breathing heavily]
[Sal] No. Oh, no.
We have to keep moving.
No, we... We can't just
leave him out there.
We need to find him!
Please, Jiuming.
- I'm sorry.
- [Sal sobbing]
He's gone.
Rigas, cover our six.
Shoot anything that moves.
You bet your ass I will.
[electricity crackling]
[tool clanking]
[Montes grunts]
[automated voice] Comms online.
[laptop trills]
What happened to you?
[Montes] The Mana One crew
stumbled upon our station.
I took them out
with a landslide.
Okay, this is...
this is out of control.
[scoffs] You authorized me
to do whatever's necessary
to protect our operation.
No. [chuckles]
They're not dead.
They are walking right now
to the station.
If they get there,
we are screwed.
- [sighs]
- [tool clatters]
[Rigas] There's still
a kilometer to go,
straight through
that valley,
and we don't have
the bioluminescence
to cover us.
[Jiuming] We're going to be
totally exposed out there.
[Jonas]
We don't have a choice.
We only have enough air
to go straight through.
[breathes deeply] Let's keep
our lights on low spectrum.
[Rigas] Yeah. We don't want
to attract the megs.
[automated voice]
One kilometer to destination.
- [Rigas exhales]
- [Jonas] O2 check?
[Meiying] 65%.
[Rigas] 50.
[Sal] 26%.
It's not gonna be enough.
[breathing heavily]
[Rigas] Hey, look at me.
Look at me.
Look at me, okay? Focus, okay?
You can do this.
Remember the training.
[Jonas] Anything on sonar?
[Jiuming] I got something,
right at the edge of my range.
Keeps going in and out.
[sonar beeps]
Stalking us.
[automated voice]
Proximity alert.
- [Meiying screams]
- [Sal] What is it?
[all grunting]
[Jonas] It's just
a shoal of fish.
[all breathing heavily]
[Jonas] Stay calm, everyone.
- [Jiuming] Are you okay?
- Yeah.
[Jonas] Keep moving.
Ayo, Mac.
We got jack
on the security footage.
Somebody deleted it.
For the sub bay?
For the whole damn station.
They're good, but they don't
know everything.
There's a satellite uplink
with an encrypted backup.
I'm gonna go
to the server room,
see if I can pull it down.
Time?
One hour, 50.
They'll be out of air soon.
I'm scanning all channels,
but nothing yet.
That's it.
Maybe 400 meters.
[automated voice] Warning.
Entering oxygen reserves.
You can do this.
- Yeah?
- Yeah. [breath trembling]
[Jiuming] I'm getting
a reading.
Many contacts to our right.
Coming in fast.
What, megs?
No. Smaller. Faster.
Everybody make it
to the station!
- Go, move!
- [automated voice] Warning.
- Oxygen level low.
- [Rigas] Come on.
- [Jonas] Come on.
- [Sal] I'm out of air.
[Jiuming] They're coming
over the ridge!
[snarling]
What are those things?
[Jiuming] It's too far.
[Jonas] We need
to make a stand!
Turn and fight!
[creatures snarling]
[grunting]
[yells]
Come on!
[creature snarling]
- [Meiying screams]
- Meiying!
[Meiying] Help!
Shoot their head!
- Meiying!
- Uncle!
[Jiuming, grunting]
I've got you!
[in Mandarin] Hold on!
[Meiying, in English]
They're biting
through the suit.
[Jonas] Meiying!
[grunting]
[creatures snarling]
[grunts]
[groans] No. No.
Hold on, Curtis!
[Sal] Too many!
We don't have a chance!
[snarling]
[tense music playing]
[creatures screeching]
Everybody stay back!
Keep going!
[Jonas] Jiuming!
[Jiuming] There's no choice.
You really want to die,
don't you?
[metal creaking]
[all grunting]
[Meiying shrieks]
Gotta make it
to the airlock!
[automated voice]
Warning. Low air.
It's no use
- I'm holding you back.
- Low air.
- It's not too far.
- [breathing heavily]
You can make it!
[automated voice]
Warning. Low air.
[Jiuming grunting]
- Warning. Low air.
- [breathing heavily, grunts]
[Jiuming gasps, yells]
[automated voice] Air depleted.
[Sal screaming]
[Jiuming screams]
[grunts, screaming]
- [Meiying] Uncle!
- [breathes heavily]
[automated voice]
Visor failure imminent.
[grunts]
[Jonas] Jiuming!
[breathing heavily, grunting]
[both breathing heavily]
[clanking]
Okay. We gotta go.
We don't have a choice.
[Jonas] He's coming
back around!
- [Curtis] Oh, God!
- [Jonas] Go, go, go!
We have to do the override.
[Curtis and Rigas panting]
[Jiuming] Come on, hurry up.
- Rigas, come on!
- [suit beeping rapidly]
[Rigas] You can do it.
Get in!
- [Meiying screams]
- Shut the door!
Curtis, you'll be okay.
[automated voice]
Suit implosion imminent.
- Almost there. Almost there!
- [Curtis] Oh, my God.
[all grunt]
It's gonna implode.
[Rigas] Depressurize the room!
- [beeping continues]
- No, no, no.
- [Implosion]
- No!
[both scream]
[somber music playing]
[Rigas] Son of a bitch!
I hate these things!
[Jonas] Hey, Rigas.
Let's try to keep it together.
We ain't out of the woods yet.
[electricity buzzing]
[footsteps echoing]
Rigas.
[Meiying] Where is everybody?
[exhales sharply]
What is that smell?
Divers.
Nobody home.
[Rigas] I'll cover the door.
Whoever's running this
is not our friend.
We need to contact
Mana One ASAP.
Think you can handle it?
Yeah. Yeah, sure.
What is this
that they're mining?
[Rigas] Whatever it is,
they're sending it
up to the surface
with these pods.
[keyboard clacking]
Mmm. Rare earth metals.
They're used
in superconductors,
aerospace
and quantum computing.
This box alone
could be a billion dollars.
"Billion" with a "B?"
Yes.
- [laptop trills]
- Mana One.
Jonas. Comms are live.
[radio static]
[Jonas] Come in.
It's Jonas. Getting this?
Hey, you're alive.
What's your status?
We lost Lance,
Sal, and Curtis.
We're at the station.
It's a rogue mining operation.
Is there anyone down there?
Not that we've seen so far.
They've infiltrated Mana One.
The rescue sub was sabotaged.
- By who?
- We're working on it.
But check this out.
I was going over the video
of when you went
over that station before.
Look at the north side.
[Jiuming] Looks like
emergency escape pods.
[Meiying] It's the opposite
side from where we are.
[Meiying] Feels dead in here.
Stay close.
These are my designs.
How do they have this?
Looks like this is it.
[Jiuming sighs]
On three.
Three.
[both grunting]
- [Jiuming] Again.
- It's not gonna work.
[both grunting]
After you.
[Rigas] Ah,
this is more like it.
Let's crack open a pod
and get out of here.
[Jiuming] Nothing here.
These controls ain't working.
We need to close the hatch.
[Rigas] On it.
[hatch whirring]
Guys, that wasn't me.
Jonas,
now that I have you here,
we need to talk candidly.
I have full control
of the station,
and I've locked down
this room.
Jess?
Your life is in my hands.
What are you doing, Jess?
These are your friends.
They've been with you
for years.
I know it hurts.
And we're talking
because I'd prefer
we were on the same side.
All making so much money,
it ceases to have meaning.
You're offering us money?
Three of our friends are dead
because of you.
You think
I'm gonna forget about that?
No, no, no, no, no!
That's the first escape pod!
Son of a bitch!
Rigas?
Rigas, you can save Meiying.
Take that speargun
and shoot Jonas in the heart.
[slurps]
[breathing heavily]
Don't shoot him.
Do it.
Go ahead.
It's the only way
Meiying survives.
Do it.
Rigas!
Do it!
[Rigas breathing heavily,
shuddering]
- Do it!
- No. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry, I can't.
I can't. I can't. [exhales]
[breathes deeply]
[breath trembling]
That was the last pod.
I told you that wouldn't work.
Put me on.
[Driscoll] Oh, sorry
it had to come to this.
So...
we'll be back at work
in a week,
using your technology
to take whatever we want.
Your institute'll be
a platform that we use
to plunder the ocean
for decades.
[in Mandarin]
Karma will get you.
[Driscoll in English]
And before you start whining
about the ecosystem,
who cares?
We'll make billions.
And no one is going to see
the damage we do.
[in Mandarin] Shut up!
[Driscoll, in English] Jess,
I've already dispatched
a clean-up crew to Mana One.
Finish this.
[metal thuds]
[Rigas] How do we
open the door?
[Jiuming] If we could
cut the comm link
to the surface...
she couldn't control anything.
[Rigas] But it's back
in the first room,
and there's no getting through
this door.
This airlock still works!
Why would you go through
the airlock? There's no pod.
I'll swim to the airlock
where we came in
and do the override.
You have no suit.
How could it work?
[Rigas] Water doesn't compress
under pressure,
so if he can force water
in his sinus cavities,
he could survive 30,
maybe 60 seconds
before he passes out.
- It is possible.
- [breathes deeply]
We work the problems
one by one.
[breathing heavily]
We do what's in front of us,
then we do the next thing.
[hatch whirring]
[Jiuming] If anyone
can do this,
it's you.
[machine buzzes]
[Meiying] Won't he be crushed
by the pressure?
[Rigas] It doesn't work
like that.
You don't see fish
wearing metal suits, do you?
It's about air.
It reacts under pressure.
And that's why he has to
blow it out of his sinuses.
[handle rattles]
- [snarls]
- [muffled grunt]
[tense music playing]
- [hatch opens]
- [alarm blares]
[water dripping]
[Montes] Hey there,
tree hugger.
Jonas Taylor, eco-warrior,
fighting the good fight.
Well, guess what?
You lost.
[chuckling]
- [coughing]
- [Montes speaking Spanish]
[in English] I spent two years
in a Manila prison
after you
and your eco-freak buddies
had our ship seized.
I thought about you
every single day.
You don't even remember me,
do you?
- Hmm?
- [breathes deeply]
[Montes] No?
Montes.
There's a million scumbags
in this world. [grunts]
It's hard to keep track
of all of 'em.
[both grunting]
[in Mandarin]
I don't think I can make it!
You can do it. It's okay.
[pants]
[both grunting]
[yells]
[machine powering up]
[grunts]
[Montes groans]
- [machine stops]
- [groans]
[in Mandarin]
We're going to die!
It's ok, it's ok.
[grunts]
[panting]
- [Jonas yelps, grunts]
- [Montes grunts]
[both grunting]
- [alarm blaring]
- [buzzes]
[both grunting]
- [alarm sounding]
- [water rushing]
Meiying!
[Jiuming and Rigas coughing]
[Jiuming gasps]
[Meiying coughing]
[helicopters whirring]
Clean up crew
approaching Mana One.
About time.
We are on alert.
Everyone confined
to their quarters.
We need to get control
of Mana One
and dispose
of any liabilities.
[DJ] What's the emergency?
[Mac] I got into
the security backup.
Look at this.
Jess disabled the rescue sub.
- What?
- Watch.
Like she could be
repairing it, right?
But no, wait.
[DJ gasps]
[Jonas] It's Montes' sub.
That's our ride out of here.
[system beeping]
[system powering up]
There's a leak
in the hydraulics.
Predator countermeasures
are down.
[sighs] We'll never make it
past the megs.
[Jiuming] We need
a distraction.
[Rigas sighs]
Light up the station.
The megs will attack it.
Yeah. And kill us.
Not if we're fast enough.
Jiuming!
[grunting]
- [Jonas] Hey, Rigas.
- Yep?
For a moment, I thought you
were gonna kill me back there.
[sighs] Well, she did say
to shoot you in the heart.
And I know for a fact
you ain't got one of those.
[chuckles]
[grunts, breathes heavily]
[in Mandarin]
Thank you for working.
[Rigas grunts]
[electricity crackling]
[Rigas grunting]
[in English] Gotta close
the hatch, Jonas.
[Jonas yelps]
[metal creaking]
We're all gonna die.
[grunting]
He's gonna make it.
No, he's not.
[Jiuming yelps]
- He's gonna make it.
- No!
We have to close the hatch!
[screams, grunts]
- [Rigas] Close it! Jonas!
- [alarm blaring]
[gasps]
[Jiuming] I'm here!
[grunts]
- [Jonas] That's him!
- [grunts]
[panting]
[Jonas] That was close.
Too close.
You should have shut
the hatch.
Yeah.
Meiying would have killed me.
You thought about it, though.
Yeah. We thought about it.
Didn't we, Rigas?
[sighs] Shut up.
Just a little bit.
[in Mandarin] Very funny.
[chuckling]
[Jiuming, in English]
Explosives?
Check this out.
Look what else.
[Meiying] Is that gonna be
a problem?
[Jiuming] It's a hole
in the thermal layer.
It must have been caused
by the mining explosions.
It will seal up eventually.
Eventually?
Yeah. Within an hour.
[Meiying] Can the megs
follow us through?
[Jiuming] I hope not.
[grunting]
Boys,
I don't want to harm you,
but I do need you
to come out of this room.
It's Jess.
She's got three soldiers.
[DJ] Yeah. It's go time.
Take this.
- The hell is this?
- It's a Taser.
Open up.
They tried to kill Jonas,
they're definitely
gonna kill us.
Okay, listen.
Here's the plan.
On the count of three,
you'll open the door
and I'mma pepper spray 'em.
Right, and you'll shut the door
and you're gonna wait.
Then go out there
and use the Taser.
One, two, three.
[mercenaries screaming,
groaning]
- [DJ] No, Mac, no! No, Mac...
- [Mac screams]
[Mac] It burns! It burns!
[screaming]
- [DJ] I'm sorry!
- [Taser crackling]
Sleepy time.
[suspenseful music playing]
- What's that?
- [computer beeping]
Trouble.
[Rigas] So, we're walking fast
and with
a lot of determination,
which is great.
But what exactly
is the plan here?
They're armed and we're not.
[breathes deeply]
[Rigas] All righty.
So what are you thinking?
What are you thinking?
You and I find Mac and DJ.
Rigas, grab what you can.
Secure a Zodiac
so we can get off this thing.
[exhales] Rock and roll.
Safest if Meiying
goes with you.
[indistinct radio chatter]
I'll protect her with my life.
And I'll protect her
with mine.
No.
[Jonas] No.
Let's go.
[DJ] I told you to wait
before you went out that door.
- How's your eyes?
- My eye stings.
[grunts] If we climb up
to the communications array,
we can bypass the DCC
and we can call for help.
What are we supposed to say?
Uh... terrorist action?
- Yeah, good. Terrorist action.
- Yeah, terrorist action.
- [DJ] Okay.
- You got a better idea?
- [mercenary] Freeze!
- [Mac yelps]
Oh, no.
[all grunting]
DJ! DJ!
[grunts]
What the hell?
Wow! Yeah, baby!
Get some!
- Hey.
- Run, Mac! Run!
- [Mac yelps]
- [DJ] Go, go, go!
[Mac grunting]
[both scream]
[mercenary] Spread out!
Find 'em.
[grunts] You got Tasers?
Now you can swim?
All of a sudden you run around
like you're frickin' Batman.
- Hell yeah.
- [both panting]
After last time,
y'all begged me to come back.
-"DJ, oh, we family, DJ."
- [gunfire]
"DJ, we need you."
Yeah, all right. Bet.
But I ain't stupid.
I trained up,
I learned how to fight,
I learned how to swim,
and I will never go anywhere
without my survival pack.
- Survival pack?
- Yeah.
Check this out.
Mmm-hmm. Come here, baby.
Come here.
Bam. [exhales]
Yeah, I even made
poison-tipped bullets,
just like Jaws 2.
- [DJ grunts]
- [mercenaries scream]
Come on, DJ!
Let's go, let's go.
[both panting]
This is insane.
[mercenary 1] Freeze, assholes.
[mercenary 2] Yeah, freeze.
You got this?
[DJ] That was some
unfortunate shit back there.
[Jiuming] No, please!
Don't shoot!
[grunts, gasps]
[in Mandarin] I know you're
looking for me and Jonas.
I also know
you don't speak Chinese,
but I'm speaking it
to distract you guys,
because my friend is about
to attack you from behind.
[in English] What?
[mercenaries grunting]
[both grunt]
- [DJ yells]
- [Jiuming] sucker.
[pants]
[exhales]
I thought you were dead.
[chuckling]
- [Jiuming grunts]
- Wishful thinking, Mac.
[DJ] If it ain't
the deviated septum.
- Boat's leaving.
- [DJ scoffs]
[Jess] What's our status?
[mercenary] Bravo team
are inbound.
ETA, ten minutes.
Excellent.
Uh, what are you doing here?
[Jess chuckles]
[Montes] Mmm.
[breathes deeply]
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
Jonas is on Mana One.
We need to lock this place
down now.
- [sighs]
- [tablet beeps]
Search the station
top to bottom.
Secure personnel
in their quarters,
kill anyone else.
Go! Go!
Oh, my God.
Uh, guys?
We've got a big problem.
[ominous music playing]
[Jess, over phone]
We tracked three megs
that escaped
before the breach closed.
We're gonna need
a good cover story for this.
Well, that shouldn't be hard.
Everyone knows Jonas
and Jiuming were reckless.
No, we need a hero.
Like, someone to emerge
from this
unforeseeable tragedy,
who can step into
a leadership position
at the Institute.
Jess, are you ready
for promotion?
I appreciate your confidence.
Jess!
It's from
the thermocline breach.
But you can relax.
This place? Meg-proof.
I mean, Jonas was
always afraid of this,
but I think, between trackers
and gunships,
we can solve the problem
and come out the other side
with a significant positive
PR spin.
Yeah, I'm on it.
I was also thinking...
[yells]
- [Meiying yelps]
- [Rigas grunts]
[Montes yelling]
[screams]
What now?
It's our only way off.
We have to take it.
But that thing
doesn't have the range
to get us to the mainland.
You're worried about
the destination?
What about
the first hundred yards?
That's where we goin' die.
We paddle out slow.
No engines.
Minimal motion.
We won't look like food.
When we're clear,
we make a run for it. Huh?
Let's do it.
[DJ] I still think
we look like food.
[Jiuming] Shh.
Quiet, everyone.
Paddle slowly.
This feels
unpleasantly familiar.
I just hope it goes better
than last time.
What happened last time?
You don't wanna know.
[Jiuming] Oh.
Here he comes.
[tense music playing]
[commander] Go, go, go!
Let's not
bring 'em back alive.
[engine starts]
You do know how to
drive this thing, right?
Stop! Stop the engine
right now.
Or you will attract the megs.
Okay. Be still.
- No motion whatsoever.
- [engine stops]
I have the shot.
Take it.
- Get down!
- [mercenary] Mate, do your job.
- Take the bloody shot.
- It's not easy as it looks.
[mercenaries screaming]
[DJ] He got 'em!
He ate 'em!
He ate the whole boat!
What happened?
[Montes, over phone]
Jess is dead.
- What?
- We stabilized Mana One
but Taylor and Zhang
have escaped.
What do you want me to do?
[Driscoll] Fix it! Kill them!
You do this,
you write your own ticket.
You are set for life.
Okay.
There's only a couple places
they could make it to.
- Are you crying, Montes?
- [line disconnects]
[canister hisses]
Any sign of the megs?
Negative.
There's no way
this thing's gonna work.
It's gonna work.
Bloke, you got more chance
of blowing up yourself
than one of the megs.
At least I won't get eaten.
Ha, I hear that.
Jo, can you make me one?
I got you covered, Mac.
We have to find a way
to warn people.
In case the megs
move towards land.
There's an island 60 klicks
southeast of us.
It's listed as inhabited.
Inhabited by who?
The name more or less
translates to...
Fun Island.
Fun Island?
[upbeat Mandarin song plays]
[people cheering]
[all] Yeah!
[indistinct chatter, laughter]
[host] Welcome to Fun Island.
Our resort has everything.
The restaurant, amazing.
The disco, incredible.
- And our spa, to die for.
- [man] Oh.
- [woman] Oh.
- [host] OMG.
It's our special dish.
Seafood Surprise!
Wow! I wouldn't know
where to start.
Well, just don't miss out
on the grilled shark.
- [dog whines]
- Pippin! Pippin!
Pippin!
- Whoa, what is that?
- [host] Pippin!
[tourist] What are
they running from?
[businessman] Your first time
at the rodeo?
[barks]
I worked with your dad since
before you were born.
I never had this kind
of trouble from him.
[in Mandarin]
Can you put your phone down?
After all these hard years
we're finally on vacation,
savor the moment.
[businessman, in English]
Yeah, and I yelled at him too.
[in Mandarin]
I've already got 400 likes.
[speaks Mandarin]
[in English]
I'm sitting in paradise
and you are ruining it!
Who does that? Who...
ruins paradise
for other people?
[upbeat song
continues playing]
Hey, baby.
Wanna rub some oil on my back?
No? [chuckles]
How 'bout my front?
[chuckling]
Ew.
[in Mandarin] Come over.
[indistinct chatter]
What?
[romantic music playing]
[chuckles]
What are you doing?
[chuckles, speaks Mandarin]
[in Mandarin]
Yaoyao...
Will you marry me?
Find it, idiot!
Wait!
Have you found it?
- [squelching]
- [water splashing]
[grunts]
[in English] Hey.
Yaoyao.
- Yaoyao! Yaoyao!
- [boat thuds]
[people screaming]
[ominous music playing]
[people grunting, gasping]
[people coughing]
[woman shrieking]
[yelps]
[woman shrieks]
This doesn't look good.
Rigas, get us there fast!
[engine revving]
Kill the cell phone uplink.
[Driscoll] There's a lot
of exposure for us on this.
Take care of Jonas
and his team quickly,
and quietly.
[Jonas] Everybody
out of the water!
- [Mac] Shark! Shark!
- [Jonas] Get back on the beach!
- Get out of the water!
- [Jiuming speaking Mandarin]
Get back on the beach, every...
[laughing]
[man, over radio] Mobile comms
are down. Over.
[birds chirping]
[distant gunfire]
[speaks Spanish]
[foreboding music playing]
[creature calling]
- [screams]
- [creature snarls]
[man screaming]
[both grunting]
- [shrieks]
- [creature snarls]
[in English] You copy, guys?
[snarling]
- [mercenary] Crocodile!
- [mercenaries clamoring]
What is that?
- [mercenary] Move, move!
- Get into the chopper.
- Now! Go with her!
- [gunfire]
[roaring]
Mmm. Mmm.
[indistinct chatter]
- [gunfire]
- [creature snarling]
[people clamoring, screaming]
[Jonas] Everybody out!
[Mac] Shark!
[Jiuming] Shark!
- [in Mandarin] Go back!
- Don't go into the water!
There's a shark!
[Jonas, in English]
Get on the beach!
Go back!
We have to save them.
- I'm not leaving ya.
- Cell phone's down.
Hello? Hello?
- [Mac] No signal.
- There's no choice.
- She's right.
- [Mac] We got no signal, guys.
Hey, you two!
Find a way to call for help.
Let everyone know
what happened.
Come on! Come on!
This way! This way!
You're gonna hide.
See that lifeguard tower?
- Yeah.
- You go there
and you stay there.
This is not
one of those things
where I tell you
to do something,
you say "yes,"
and then you do
whatever you want.
Understand?
Yes.
You're not messing with me?
No.
I can't do what I need to do
if I'm worried about you.
I'll be fine.
Promise me
you'll come back.
You know I love you.
[boat pedals squeaking]
[screaming]
[squeaking]
[people screaming]
[screaming]
Oh, shit.
[distant gunfire]
Sonny.
- Check that out.
- [helicopter powers down]
Hey, yo, my man.
You got a phone?
[people screaming]
What's everyone running from?
[creature snarls]
What the hell was that?
[Jonas] Three megs.
Three of us.
We each grab a jet ski.
Get them to chase it away
from these people
and out to sea.
Then we harpoon them.
Oh, you mean
with those jerry-rigged,
maybe-they-work,
maybe-they-kill-us harpoons?
Yeah.
It's a terrible idea.
You got a better one?
No. No.
- Then we're agreed.
- Yeah.
- Good.
- Great.
[gunfire]
[creature roars]
[creature growling]
Montes!
Shit.
[sighs]
[creature snarls]
[snarling]
[screaming]
[DJ] Let's go old school.
The landline's down, too.
Okay, coast is clear.
Let's go.
They can walk?
[roars]
Shit.
It's those things.
They haven't spotted us yet.
- Okay.
- [creatures snarl]
[Rigas exhales]
[creature snarls]
What else you got in here?
Emergency stuff.
[unzips bag]
Okay.
[sighs]
Really? Condoms?
Different kind of emergencies.
Hand me that.
Now hand me
that gum in your mouth.
Thank you.
[snarls]
[people screaming]
There's only one ski.
Give me your harpoons.
You sure?
Oh...
- I got this.
- [Mac] Good luck.
We need more firepower.
Yeah.
I have an idea.
Let's go.
Not this time, Taylor.
Vamos.
[Jiuming] This should be
the place.
Come on.
What are we looking for?
Ammonium nitrate.
You're making a bomb?
This stuff is
as powerful as TNT.
- [mercenary] Hey!
- [creature snarls]
- [gunfire]
- Get in! Get in!
- [all clamoring]
- [explosion]
Freeze!
[dramatic music playing]
Come on!
[engine sputtering]
[engine starts]
[roars]
[DJ] Come on, let's see
if he's got a phone.
[creature snarls]
I got the sat phone.
I got the sat...
I got the phone.
Why you stealing his money?
- What? He's not gonna need it.
- [snarling]
Uh-oh.
- Nice doggies. Nice doggies.
- [roaring]
Okay, Rigas.
On the count of three,
we're gonna bolt.
One. Two. Three!
What the hell? Hey!
[snarls]
Wait for DJ!
[Rigas] They're right
behind us!
Let's hide in here!
Come on. Come on.
Come here. Come here.
- What the hell?
- Hi, DJ. Hi, Rigas.
- [Rigas] Whoa.
- All of you together.
Up against the wall.
Hands up!
I wouldn't point that at me
if I were you.
Trust me.
Shut it!
Keep your hands in the air.
Hands up!
Don't want to hurt you,
so I'm going
to give you one chance.
Put those weapons down.
Or you'll do what?
Stay still, little guy.
[groans]
[motor whirring]
[mercenary]
No, no! Joe, Joe, door!
- Stay where you are!
- [mercenaries clamoring]
- Go, go!
- [mercenary 2] Get to cover!
[gunfire]
[all screaming]
- [mercenaries screaming]
- [gunfire]
[all grunting]
[Jiuming groans, grunts]
Damn!
[phone beeps]
I got signal.
Call for help!
To get down to the beach
and help people!
[Mac] Where are you going?
- Stealing a chopper.
- [Mac] What chopper?
Global rescue?
We need rescue!
We need you to send
everybody you got!
The National Guard,
the lifeguard,
the Coast Guard. Anybody!
Just come now!
[engine roaring]
[tense music playing]
[explosion]
[engine stops]
[Mac] Ugh, looks like
someone else
- had the same idea.
- [creature snarling]
We need a plan.
We have to lead it away
and steal the chopper.
Okay, you lead it away,
I'll steal the chopper.
You distract it,
I'll get the chopper.
Why me?
Can you fly a chopper?
Yeah, I can.
- You have a license?
- Yes, I do!
- I didn't know that.
- What?
Okay, good plan.
[whispers] Mac!
[clanging]
[roaring]
[snarling]
[gasps]
- [gasps, grunting]
- [snarls]
- [grunting]
- [snarling]
- [grunts]
Jiuming! We gotta go!
- [snarling]
- [footsteps approaching]
[shrieks]
Fuel! Get the fuel!
Gas! We need gas!
[snarling]
Get up!
[grunts]
[Mac] Get the fuel!
[grunting]
[chitters]
- Lizard incoming! Hold on!
- [Jiuming grunts]
- [screaming]
- Jiuming? Jiuming!
- [creatures snarling]
- [grunts]
[grunts]
[Mac] Run!
Go!
[grunts]
[screams]
[Mac] Whoa, yay!
[Mac] Man,
I didn't think you were
gonna make that one.
[barking]
[people gasping]
[screaming]
[man] Run!
[screams]
[people screaming in distance]
[breath trembling] No.
[gunfire]
[Montes] Where are you going,
Jonas?
[gunfire]
[chuckles]
[people screaming]
[barking, snarling]
Get lower! That's Meiying!
[Mac] Are you sure
it's Meiying?
Get lower!
[Mac] Okay, okay!
Hold on!
[people clamoring]
[people screaming]
Meiying!
Over here!
[Jiuming] Leap up!
- [grunting]
- [alarm blaring]
[yelling]
[grunts, groans]
- [groans, gasps]
- [bomb beeping]
- [beeping stops]
- [water splashing]
[grunts]
[tense music playing]
[grunting]
[grunts]
[yelling]
[Montes] Jonas is still alive?
Get me over there!
[people screaming]
Help!
[in Mandarin]
Hang on, Meiying!
[grunts loudly]
Taylor!
Come on!
Come out from under
the bridge, little troll!
[speaking Spanish]
[speaks Spanish]
[screaming]
[both grunting]
[speaks Spanish, groans]
[sighs]
[in English]
End of the line, no?
I guess it is.
You got the gun.
I won't be needing this.
[chuckling]
I knew you couldn't do it.
[Montes grunts]
See you later, chum.
[Meiying] Jiu!
[grunting]
Meiying!
[in Mandarin]
Throw me the bomb!
[in English] Where?
[in Mandarin] Catch it!
[grunting]
[yelling]
[creature growls]
[creature groans]
[grunts]
[grunting]
[bomb beeping]
[rapid beeping]
[explosion]
[grunts]
[creature screeches]
[spluttering]
[creature screeching]
[gasping]
[in English]
Hold on! I'm coming!
[Jonas] Meiying!
Meiying!
- [Meiying] Jonas! Over here!
- [indistinct conversation]
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Uncle Jiuming
and Mac's in trouble.
Stay here.
I'll be right back.
Mac! Are you okay?
- Mac?
- [grunts]
[grunts]
[tense music playing]
[grunting]
- [metal thuds]
- [breathes heavily, grunts]
[grunts]
[yells]
Come on,
you ugly bastard!
[screams]
- [metal creaking]
- [grunting]
[yells]
[Jiuming grunts]
[panting]
[people clamoring]
Come on, come on, come on!
Come on, come on. I got you,
I got you. Come on, come on! Come on!
Watch, watch, watch it!
Come on, come on, come on!
Meiying,
what are you doing here?
I had to save the dog!
What?
- [creature snarls]
- [host] Mommy's here.
- Thank you! Thank you!
- You're welcome.
[creature snarls]
- [people gasping]
- [roaring]
- Oh, no, you don't!
- [Rigas] Meiying! Come!
[Meiying yelps]
[roars]
[DJ] Hell yeah!
Get some!
[chuckles]
Who says a .50 caliber
is an impractical round?
[grunts]
Hey! Wait, wait, wait!
[Jonas] Everyone stay still.
No motion.
No, it's okay.
That's Haiqi.
Who cares which one it is?
She'll listen to me.
Let's spread out so that thing
don't get us all.
I got this!
[device clicks, whistles]
[gasps, grunts]
Yes! I knew it!
I told you!
We have a special bond.
- It went after the dolphins.
- [Jiuming] No!
She obeyed my command.
Ridiculous.
I didn't believe it before
and I don't believe it now.
Hey, Mac,
back me up.
I'm getting out of here
before she changes her mind.
Mac!
[Mac] You guys stay there
and argue.
She obeyed my command!
- Dolphins.
- No!
It's not my fault.
Sometimes, there's a situation,
and bad things
are happening,
and you just have
to get involved.
I'm glad
you finally understand.
I'm proud of you.
[in Mandarin] Next time
don't run around, ok?
[pilot, over radio] Rescue One
to Fun Island. Over.
[DJ] Oh, it's good
to hear your voice, man.
We got a lot of people
who need help.
[DJ] Yeah,
I used to didn't know
how to swim,
but then, you know,
you out there chasing sharks,
you better learn
how to swim quick!
[women laughing]
The water was cold. It wasn't
that cold, but yeah,
- I was just having fun!
- [Rigas] What about Haiqi?
She's still out there.
- Maybe pregnant.
- ...lucky to be alive, baby.
- Oh, preferably not.
- [DJ] Know what's crazy?
Like, a few years ago...
That's tomorrow.
Today, we count our blessings.
Here's to being alive.
Here's to dolphins.
- [chuckling]
- To Meiying being safe.
[Jonas] And here's to Sal,
Lance, and Curtis.
So...
am I still grounded?
- Absolutely.
[all chuckling]
You two are ridiculous.
But I love you anyway.
[Jiuming] Mmm.
Looks like you got
a little reckless out there.
No, everything
was totally under control.
- [Jonas] Yeah, right.
- [DJ grunts]
Well, everything's about to be
totally not under control.
[DJ chuckles]
Give me some.
[DJ grunts]
[DJ] Mmm.
Yeah, that's the good stuff.
[DJ sighs]
[Jonas and Meiying chuckle]
[enthralling music playing]
[upbeat Mandarin song playing]
["Chomp" by
Page Kennedy playing]
♪ I'm on my way
And I'm hiding out ♪
♪ In the dark sea ♪
♪ Ain't no part of me
Is gonna stop biting ♪
♪ Till the artery
Is hardly repairable ♪
♪ Unbearable, be careful ♪
♪ I'm not a werewolf ♪
♪ I'm meg infested ♪
♪ Terrible ♪
♪ And I dare you to...
Dare you to... ♪
♪ Dare you ♪
♪ Get 'em out
Get 'em out ♪
♪ Chomp ♪
♪ Spit 'em out
Spit 'em out ♪
♪ Chomp, megalodon ♪
♪ Get 'em out
Get 'em out ♪
♪ Chomp, chomp ♪
♪ I'm the megalodon ♪
♪ Megalodon ♪
♪ Chomp, chomp, chomp ♪
♪ Chomp on this ♪
♪ I'm an apex predator
Ain't nothing regular ♪
♪ Nobody better than
Nah, nah ♪
♪ Chomp, chomp, chomp
Chomp, chomp, chomp ♪
♪ Chomp on this ♪
♪ I'm an apex predator
Ain't nothing regular ♪
♪ Nobody better than
Nah, nah ♪
♪ Chomp, chomp, chomp ♪
♪ Chomp on this ♪
♪ I'm an apex predator
Ain't nothing regular ♪
♪ Nobody better than
Nah, nah ♪
♪ Chomp, chomp, chomp ♪
♪ Chomp on this ♪
♪ I'm an apex predator ♪
♪ Nobody better than... ♪
♪ I'm the meg ♪
♪ I'm the egg ♪
♪ I'mma let it rain
All over you ♪
♪ Like I'm incontinent ♪
♪ And I'm pissed off
Whatever it cost you ♪
♪ Call me Criss Cross
Whether you're Rick Ross ♪
♪ So back a hip toss
From the big boss ♪
♪ Like lip gloss
So get your drip loss ♪
♪ Get 'em out
Get 'em out ♪
♪ Chomp ♪
♪ Spit 'em out
Spit 'em out ♪
♪ Chomp, megalodon ♪
♪ Get 'em out
Get 'em out ♪
♪ Chomp, chomp ♪
♪ I'm the megalodon ♪
♪ Megalodon ♪
♪ Chomp, chomp, chomp ♪
♪ Chomp on this ♪
♪ I'm an apex predator
Ain't nothing regular ♪
♪ Nobody better than
Nah, nah ♪
♪ Chomp, chomp, chomp
Chomp, chomp, chomp ♪
♪ Chomp on this ♪
♪ I'm an apex predator
Ain't nothing regular ♪
♪ Nobody better than
Nah, nah ♪
♪ Chomp, chomp, chomp ♪
♪ Chomp on this ♪
♪ I'm an apex predator
Ain't nothing regular ♪
♪ Nobody better than
Nah, nah ♪
♪ Chomp, chomp, chomp
Chomp, chomp, chomp ♪
♪ Chomp on this ♪
♪ I'm an apex predator
Nobody better than... ♪
♪ When you start seein' ♪
♪ That's when you see
People marchin' ♪
♪ As soon as they see
That shark fin ♪
♪ They run into the land
Like Martin ♪
♪ Your apartment, your house
Your flight, your car's in ♪
♪ Watch me start this arson ♪
♪ Eat my own kind ♪
♪ I'mma rip your apartment ♪
♪ Chomp, chomp, chomp ♪
♪ Chomp on this ♪
♪ I'm an apex predator
Ain't nothing regular ♪
♪ Nobody better than
Nah, nah ♪
♪ Chomp, chomp, chomp
Chomp, chomp, chomp ♪
♪ Chomp on this ♪
♪ I'm an apex predator
Nobody better than... ♪
♪ Chomp, chomp, chomp ♪
♪ Chomp on this ♪
♪ Nobody better than... ♪
[dramatic music playing]